Roxanne Beaver

Windows Program Manager, Windows, Windows Scenario Adoption and Breadth Engagement Team - Microsoft Corporation

Issaquah, WA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Roxanne-Beaver/38456d4e7cbd61b5

- 18+ years of PM experience in the Windows Division and Enterprise Services Teams for Microsoft Corporation.
- Strong self-motivator with willingness to obtain skills, take-on challenges, and work with teams, to create new processes.
- Impeccable documentation skills including: Patent Disclosure Documents, Vision Plans, Requirement lists and their dependencies, Specifications, Schedules, DCRs, Release Criteria, Release Notes, Best Practices, FAQs, and Post-Mortems.
- Excellent Serviceability skills: Experienced at defining and delivering Hot Fixes, QFEs, and Service Packs for Windows.

Microsoft Technical Patents and Program Management Awards:

- June 2012: Windows "Star Award": Releasing all Building Windows 8 blog videos that reached over 7.5 million views.
- Feb. 2007: Microsoft Technical Patent: Gathering User Feedback to be packaged and shared.
- Aug. 2006: Windows International "Star Award": Releasing all Windows XPSE languages for XPSP2x2.
- Mar. 2006: Microsoft Technical Patent: Obtaining User Feedback in a Networking Environment.
- Sep. 2005: Windows XP Starter Edition "Star Award": Extensive process redesign for XPSE localization releases.
- Jan. 2002: Localization Studio "Customer Satisfaction Award": Cross-group collaboration and negotiation skills with Office.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Windows Program Manager, Windows, Windows Scenario Adoption and Breadth Engagement Team

Microsoft Corporation -

November 2010 to Present

Developed a new Design Agency Program for Windows to build relationships with Designers to build innovative Windows Store apps.

- Created a videography studio and recorded all Building Windows 8 blog videos for Steven Sinofsky (President of Windows).
- Collaborated with UEX, Windows PR, and Waggener Edstrom to produce several PR videos shown at the // build/ event. Both the Intern and Windows Engineering videos were shown to 5K people at //build/. The Intern video was also shown at the company meeting to 90K MS employees worldwide.
- Collaborated with Leila Toplic's team to create a series of video vignettes to deliver to the field. The videos were used to increase the fields' sales force and get them up to speed on the Windows 8 story. 45K field members were required to take the training prior to the end of the quarter.

Senior Consultant, Microsoft Services Enterprise Strategy & Architecture, ESA Team

Microsoft Corporation -

March 2012 to October 2012

For Microsoft Corporation)

March 2012 - Oct 2012:

Senior Consultant, Microsoft Services Enterprise Strategy & Architecture, ESA Team (formerly ITAP)

- Identified the top 10% of highest-performing Enterprise Advisors at Microsoft. Top Enterprise Advisors were chosen to enroll in a new Enterprise Advisor training program and given the most significant Enterprise Customer accounts for FY'11.
- Wrote 15 Technical Patent Disclosure Documents including all conceptual diagrams of features.
- Facilitated meetings with Microsoft Legal and the Enterprise Services team to review technical patent documents for submission to the US Patent and Trademark Office.
- Microsoft LCA review of Roxanne's patents: " Great job on writing your disclosures. The team sees many submissions all year long and wish more (patents) were as well written as the documents we've received from your team."

International Project Manager & Release Manager

Microsoft Corporation -

2006 to 2009

Windows International, Windows Localization Team

- Facilitated Windows 7 PowerShell & ADML group policy files for all required language sets for Windows 7.
- Delivered Windows Vista LIP High-level Process Overview, Vista LIP Schedules, and supporting planning documents for all of the Windows Vista LIP languages.
- Released 7 Windows Vista LIP languages by aligning International Vendors, Moderators, Engineers, Test and internal teams to adhere to a highly interdependent workflows, schedules, and quality measures.

Release Manager, Windows International

Emerging Markets Team -

2004 to 2006

Released 29 Windows XP Starter Editions languages to over 140 different countries including market-region specific content including wallpapers, screensavers, and localized videos.

- Facilitated project team assessment meetings with GM and Director-level employees to reduce ambiguity within the Project to identify project risks, impacts and solutions.
- Delivered new tools to improve the Windows XP Started Edition build process to ensure high-quality builds for testing.

Release Manager & Program Manager

Productivity Tools, Localization Studio Team -

1999 to 2004

Released all Hot Fixes, QFEs, and Milestone releases for LocStudio tools: LocStudio Build tools, LocStudio client, LocStudio Parsers and TBXHub (TermStudio).

- Wrote Specification documents, Schedules, Role Security limitations, Language Identifier lists, and created a DCR process and a Release Criteria template.
- Drove Product Localization teams from Windows, Office, VS, WSS, and MSN on a regular basis to gather requirements and drive product-specific releases based on partner Product road-maps.

Technical Writer, Consumer Products & Windows

-

1994 to 1999

Saxon & Taylor Onsite)

• Wrote help documentation for Source Depot v1.0 and v1.1.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Technical Writing and Editing

University of Washington - Seattle, WA

1998

Bachelor of Arts in Psychology

Washington College - Chestertown, MD

1993